Finding Aid for the Doreen Gehry Nelson Method of Design-Based Learning (formerly City Building Education™) Records LSC.2239
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Design-Based Learning Files
  - Cal Poly Pomona files
    - Kathleen Brown, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      Materials include a fax from Nelson to Brown and an invitation to a supper honoring Brown, "California's Next Governor."
    - Faye Carey, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Chaparral Middle School, 2013 (Box 74, Folder 13)
      Materials include a DBL Classrooms Grand Opening Ceremony and Ribbon Cutting Leslie A. Stoltz Dedication brochure.
    - Cooper Hewitt, 2007 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Smithsonian Cooper Hewitt, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Cooper Hewitt Eames, 1999 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Cooper Hewitt, 1995-1997 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Converge magazine, 2001 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Co-op learning book review, 1986 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - ChiChi Pierce, 2000 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      Materials include correspondence with Pierce of the Doc Tank, Inc. concerning the 3-D & I media program.
    - Chicago Design Inst., 1996 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Children's Museum, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Center for Children & Technology, 1999 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Cranbrook Michigan, 1998 June (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - CD-Rom Design World (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Meredith Davis, 1999 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - A 4E Dream Team, 2009 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Dee Dickerson, 1999 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Dhir, Harpreet, 2003 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Dow Chemical, 1971-1975 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Dunn Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Betty Edwards, 1993 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Edison Projects, 1992-1993 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Alan Feigenberg, 2000 June 24 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Girls in the Band, 2011 July (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Glendale USD, 2009-2011 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Galef, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 8)
      Materials include correspondence with the Galef Institute.
    - Lev Gonick, 2007 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Roger Hart, 1990 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Heller Foundation, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Humanitas, 2010 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Hale after school program, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - ITAC TV/Radio (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - IIDA, 1998-2000 (Box 76, Folder 15)
      Materials include Nelson's correspondence with the International Interior Design Association (IIDA).
    - Fernandez photos, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 16)
      One CD.
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
      Materials include slides, photos and a CD of of Miguel Fernandez's students.
    - Israel, 1997 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Japan, 2008-2009 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Ted Kahn, 1997 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Kaiser Permanente, 2012 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Herb Kohl, 1990-2000 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Materials include correspondence with Herbert Kohl, an educator who influenced Nelson's work and used her book for teaching his classes.
    - LAAAE training, 2011 August (Box 77, Folder 6)
      This folder contains a staff development packet for a one day training at the LA Academy of Arts and Enterprise (LAAAE).
    - LAAAE minutes, 2009-2010; This folder contains LAAAE Board of Directors meeting minutes. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Lotus, 1998-2000, 2007 (Box 78, Folder 1-4)
      Correspondence, workshop agendas, and work plans for professional staff development at Lotus Music and Dance Studios.
    - Long Beach Aquarium, 2003-2004 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Legal, 1992-1995 (Box 78, Folder 6-8)
      Correspondence concerning legal matters with Apple, Taligent, and CBE rip-offs.
    - Miami, 2011 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Paul MacCready, 2000-2007 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      Biography/History
      Paul MacCready was an aerospace scientist who championed Nelson's work. Nelson worked on a project with Paul at Mashall Middle School in Pomona Unified School District called "Hamster Driven Aircraft - Doing More with Less." They trained a super star hamster to be a power source for lifting a small aircraft which could fly from one desk to another about one foot off the ground. Their point was to teach students about never before seen ways of finding energy.
      Correspondence, clippings, articles, and a MacCready memorial program.
    - Wayne McIntyre, 2007 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Materials include a Los Angeles Times obituary for McIntyre, a professor of Nelson's who encouraged her to realize CBE.
    - Maxis, 1998 August (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Jay Rounds, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      Materials include correspondence with Rounds of the Milken Family Foundation.
    - Inabeth Miller (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Science Museum of Minnesota, 1991-1996 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Robert Garfinkle, Project Leader of The Real Life of Buildings.
    - MIT, 1991-1993 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with Professor Stephen A. Benton, Head of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Program in Media Arts & Sciences.
    - Steven Moss, 1999 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Multi-Media roundtable, 1994 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - NY Foundation for the Arts, 1999 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Neutra house, 1990 July (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Photos, slides and correspondence concerning Nelson's use of the Neutra House for "A City in the Classroom" workshop.
    - North Carolina State University, 2001 February 12-14 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Meredith Davis, 1998, 2007 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      Materials include a copy of Davis' "Making a Case for Design-Based Learning."
    - N.E.A., 2000 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Materials include The National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) 1965-2000: A Brief Chronology of Federal Support for the Arts.
    - Norberto Nardi, 1999-2000 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Otis Cert. Prog. Proposal, 1984 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      Materials include a description of the Curriculum Design credential at Otis/Parsons School of Design in Los Angeles.
    - Open School, 1994 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Prentice Hall-Merrill Educ., 2000-2001 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Pasadena USD, 2014 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Bill Poms, 2007 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Riverside School for the Arts, 1998 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Phyllis Rosser, 1997-1998 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - SIFT, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 3)
      Materials include Art Center's Summer Institute for Teachers (SIFT) scholarship brochures.
    - Skirball, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Alison and Peter Smithson, 1988 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      In 1978 Peter taught at UCLA and lived in Nelson's house. Nelson corresponded with the Smithsons until they both died. Peter was also friends with Charles Eames but did not know Nelson's brother because in 1978, Frank Gehry was not a household name.
      Materials include correspondence from English architects, Peter and Alison Smithson.
    - John Steinmetz, 1991-1994 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      Materials include correspondence concerning electronic music pioneer Morton Subotnick's visit to the Open School, his research notes on The Unschool of the 21st Century and his article, "Creative Teamwork."
    - Stoltz - general info., 2008-2013 (Box 81, Folder 7)
      Materials include correspondence with Stoltz concerning her work with Nelson, letters regarding Stoltz's funeral services and the Leslie Stoltz Scholarship Fund.
    - Scholastic - Francie Alexander, 1997 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Project Zero - Harvard, 1993 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Talking City, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Teacher brochures, 1999 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      Materials include two Civilization Building Core teacher brochures made by kids.
    - Testimonials, 1998-2010 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      Materials include thank you cards made by Nelson's students and DBL evaluation forms.
    - UCLA facilities planning, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - University of New Mexico, 1993 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      Materials include correspondence with Bob Weber of the University's College of Education and School of Law and flyers for Weber's publication, "Forks, Phonographs, & Hot Air Balloons."
    - Venturi, 1996 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - West Virginia, 1996 March (Box 82, Folder 7)
      Materials include Marshall University "Design Influences" Symposium on Design brochures and related correspondence.
    - Whole Earth Ecology, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 8)
      Materials include a review of Nelson's Transformations book and a letter from a Whole Earth Review research department staff member.
    - World Design/Peter Lowe, 2000 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Minneapolis - Weisman Art, 1999 August 23-24 (Box 82, Folder 10)
      Materials include brochures and evaluations for the "Spaces and Places: Teaching Art and Design through the Internet" conference at The Frederick R. Weisman Art Museum.
    - Wang Award, 2006 (Box 82, Folder 11-12)
      Correspondence, Nelson's selection committee packet, invitations, guest lists, and CSU programs which feature Nelson as the award recipient for Education, and Professional and Applied Sciences.
    - Pomona letters of thanks, 1986-2001 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Masters concentrated CB programs, undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - David Greene, 1988-1990 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - DN tenure at Cal Poly, 1986-1988 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - MA - History of Creation, 1989-1996 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Fall advising, 1991 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Brochures, 1992 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Sabbatical, 1992-1994 (Box 83, Folder 8-9)
      Folder 9 includes a letter of support from Apple Fellow Alan Kay.
    - DBL MA posters, circa 1995 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Seven DBL MA posters announce Design and Creativity in Education courses at Cal Poly Pomona.
    - Authorization to travel forms, 1996-2006 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Cal Poly bulletins, 1998-2001 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Global - Cal Poly Pomona, 1999 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Post-tenure review, 1999-2000 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Sabbatical, 1999-2000 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Cal Poly Pomona Abroad article, circa 2000 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - M.A. program presentation, 2002 November 14 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Sabbatical, 2002-2003 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Use of Private Vehicle, 2003-2008 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - M.A. program info sheet, 2004 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - DBL brochures, 2004 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Sabbatical, 2004-2005 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Polytrends, 2005 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - GIA speech outline, 2005 October 18 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Golden Bell Award, 2006 (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - M.A. graduation, 2006 (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Course grades & evals, 2006-2007 (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - Annual academic personnel evaluation, 2007-2008 (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - Course grades & evals, 2007-2008 (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Chinese delegation, 2008 December 3 (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - NBS Instant City of Feelings plan, undated (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - Pathway Graphics samples, 1998 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Sustainable coastal community plans, 2003 (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Course grades & evals, 2009 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - DBL certificate, 2009-2010 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Course evals & grades, 2010-2011 (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
    - Gavin Newsom correspondence, 2011 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Course grades & evals, 2011-2012 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - DBL correspondence (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Sabbatical, 2012 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Course evaluations, 2013 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Chaparral M.S. correspondence, 2013 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Curriculum layout, 2014 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - M.A. program handouts, undated (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - M.A. projects, undated (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - DBL handout, undated (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Cal Poly faculty guide, undated (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Slides and photos, 1995-2004 (Box 86, Folder 1-8)
      Folders 1-5: Slides of Cal Poly Pomona M.A. students.
      Folders 6-8: Photos of Nelson with her M.A. students, U.S.-Japan Architecture and Children International Symposium, and curriculum maps.
    - Videotapes, 1995-2002 (Box 87, Box 88)
      Box 87: Thirteen VHS tapes include the following titles: Final presentation course #2, Presentation of lesson course #1, D. Nelson M.A. class, Design World, Alan Kay, Martin Haberly, Michael Eisenberg, Betty Edwards Drawing Demo, Jerry Yang, Herb Kohl and Monton Subot.
      Box 88: Twelve VHS tapes include the following titles: ROP Design Based, DBL Promo, Flying Free, Ron Hockwalt, Macready Sturges, Laurel Adler and Sue Griffin.
  - Art Center files
    This subseries includes flyers, publications, mailers, programs, brochures, agendas and evaluations for Nelson's DBL Kids Program, Learning Lab, and Summer Institute for Teachers (SIFT) at Art Center College of Design.
    - Art Center Kids Program, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Art Center travel, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Art Center Summer, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 3-4)
      Folder 3 includes evaluations, brochures and agendas for Nelson's first DBL Summer Institute for Teachers.
      Folder 4 contains nine Summer Institute mailers.
    - Art Center Summer, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 5-6)
    - Art Center General, 2003-2004 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Art Center Summer, 2004 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Full Circle, 2004 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Open House invitations, 2004 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Public programs booklet, 2004 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - AIGA at Art Center, 2005 February 5 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Dot Magazine, 2005 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Art Center Summer, 2005-2006 (Box 90, Folder 6-7)
    - SIFT evaluations, 2007 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - SIFT and peer coaching evaluations, 2007-2008 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - SIFT handouts, 2008 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Art Center Summer, 2009 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Art Center SIFT, 2010-2012 (Box 92, Folder 1-3)
    - At a Glance - DBL, undated (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - South Campus Fact Sheet, undated (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - DBL Learning Lab brochures, 2004-2005 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Art Center DBL flyers, 2003-2005 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Art Center Summer, 2014 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Audiovisual materials, 2001-2009 (Box 94)
      Fifteen CDs, six DVDs, three zip discs, three Mini DVs and one Hi8 cassette provide documentation of Nelson's DBL Art Center work.
- Publications, 1966-
  The publications series includes books, magazines, journals, reports, newspapers and clippings collected by Nelson. Almost all publications either include articles on Nelson's work with CBE and DBL or were created by Nelson.
  - The Object Transformed, 1966 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Goals for the Los Angeles Region, 1967 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - The Source newspapers, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Summary Report of the Los Angeles Goals Council, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - CBE clippings binder, 1969-1982 (Box 95, Folder 5-8)
  - Educational Goals in an Urban Setting, 1970 (Box 96, Folder 1-2)
    Two copies of Nelson's M.A. thesis wherein Nelson presents the theoretical educational model which provides the framework that informed her CBE methodology.
  - Mobil Classrooms, 1970 (Box 96, Folder 3-4)
    These folders each contain one copy of a paper Nelson wrote for her Master's program entitled, "A Future Model of Schools."
  - Articles, 1970 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - The Source, 1970 April (Box 96, Folder 6)
    The Source newspaper was a Venice publication by Citizens for Political Integrity. The front page of this issue features the headline, "..and a child shall lead us" for a story about the CBE work Nelson's students were engaged with while working on a Master Plan for Venice. The editorial page highlights Nelson's Westminster Elementary School fifth and sixth grade students' letters to Mayor Yorty and Councilman Braude concerning their visions for the future of Venice.
  - The Source newspapers, 1970 May-June (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Claes Oldenburg and L.A. architecture clippings, circa 1970 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - My Weekly Reader, 1971 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Smithsonian, 1971 May (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1971 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Smithsonian book, 1971 (Box 97, Folder 1-3)
    Materials include the book by Nelson and her brother Frank Gehry, correspondence, and paste-up boards.
  - Follow the Yellow Brick Roads, 1979 April (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Dimensions: A Catalog of Ideas Relating Education to Work, 1978 (Box 97, Folder 5-6)
  - The Contemporary, 1984 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Learning to Get Around, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - My Weekly Reader, 1971 September 15 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Our Man-Made Environment resource guides, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - MOCA article - original art, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - CBEP documentation booklets, 1971-1972 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1971-1973 (Box 98, Folder 6-8)
  - Architecture and Environmental Planning booklet, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - The CBEP: A Decision-Making Approach to Education, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - CBE Writings - General, 1973-1974 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - The CBEP: A Design for Elementary Education, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Alternative Learning Environments, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - CBEP Summer Orientation guide, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - CBE: Architectural Consultant Edition, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - CBE Program, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Manual for the CBE Program, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - The CBEP: A Design for Elementary Education, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Tiger cartoon strip, circa 1970s (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - The CBE Program: A Problem Solving...draft, circa 1974 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Documentation for the CBEP: Architect Consultant, 1974 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1974-1975 (Box 100, Folder 4-5)
  - Seeing the Environment, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - CBEP: Architectural Consultant Edition, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Learning magazines, 1975 October (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Diagnosis & Remediation of the Disabled Reader excerpt, 1976 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1976 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Our Own Expressions, 1976 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Ms. Magazine, 1976 May (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Brochure originals, circa 1977 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1977 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Instant Object, 1977 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Position Paper, 1978 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1978 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - CB: Learning Through the Arts Program, 1978 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Classroom as City, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Using the City: Law & Humanities in the CBEP, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Smithsonian, 1979 February (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - CBE Final Eval Report, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Article about CBE, 1979 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Ms. Magazine, 1979 November (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Update on Law Related Education, 1979 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Design Arts, 1980 August (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - CBE articles, undated (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Learning about the Built Environment, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - CBE Final Evaluation Report, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Daring to Dream, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Arts and the Schools, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - CBE: The City as a Legal Construct, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 11-13)
  - CBE Prospectus, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - L.A. Architect, 1981 July (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - 3-D Tools for Making Connections originals, 1981 (Box 103, Folder 1-6)
  - L.A. Architect, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - ABC Training Manual, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - CBE System Trainer's Manual, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - CBE Proposal for a Teacher Peer Training Program and Lab/Idea Bank, 1982 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - What is CBE?, 1982 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - A Tribute to Alan Sieroty, 1982 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1982-1983 (Box 104, Folder 8-9)
  - CBE: A Way to Learn, 1982-1983 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - CBE: A Way to Learn, 1983 (Box 105, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - MOCA articles by DGN, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Transformations: Process & Theory, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 5-6)
  - Articles, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - The Living City, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Walker Art Center program and brochures, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Visible Objects are part of Invisible Ideas, 1988 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - 15 Journal, 1989 May (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy of Education Proceedings, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Annual Review of Environmental Education, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Children's Environments Quarterly, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Growing by Design conference program, 1990 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Scientific American, 1991 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1991 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - NY Times: Education Life, 1991 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Change and Creativity guidebook, undated (Box 106, Folder 10-11)
  - Articles, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Open: Thoughts, Feelings, Fantasies, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - The Harvard Education Letter, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Cooper-Hewitt..., 1992 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Children's Environments, 1992 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - SIM City Teacher's Guides, 1993 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Children's Enviroments journal, 1993 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Changing Arch. of Teacher's Minds article, 1993 December (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1994-1995 (Box 107, Folder 6-7)
  - How the Brain Works...by Pat Wolfe, 1996 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Open Charter School pubs., 1996, 1998 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1997 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - CB: The Designer as Teacher, 1997 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Design as a Catalyst for Learning, 1997 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - OMG Center - Linkages, 1998 (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Cal Poly Pomona Bulletins, 1999 March 15 (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1999 (Box 107, Folder 15)
  - Cal Poly Pomona Abroad, circa 2000 (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Perspective - Backward Thinking, 2000 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Marshall University on DN, undated (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 2000 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Perspective, 2000 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Instant City of the Future Tool Kit, 2001 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Converge, 2001 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - CBE E-Article, 2001 August 29 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Cal Poly Pomona Bulletins, 2001 February 12 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies, 2004 (Box 108, Folder 9-10)
  - Articles, 2004 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - DOT Magazine, 2005 (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Poly Trends magazine, 2006-2007 (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - NEXT: AIGA Design Conference program, 2007 (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Committee of 300 blog, 2010 (Box 108, Folder 15)
- Accession LSC-2018-024 backlog material, LSC-2018-024; 8.3 linear feet (4 record cartons, 3 flat boxes, 2 doc boxes); 11 audiovisual carriers (10 videocassettes, 1 film strip); 16 born-digital carriers (16 optical discs); 2.83 Gigabytes (814 files, 53 folders) (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4A, Box 4B, Box 5, Box 6, Box 8, Box 9)